VADIM GRIBANOV

Cracow, Poland

+(48) 516 937 979 \diamond mail@vadimgribanov.com \diamond Github \diamond Linkedin

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer who loves to create awesome products that meet user needs. I have more than nine years of experience and a track record of delivering successful products. When faced with complex technical problems, I have a knack for troubleshooting and analyzing issues. I work well with others and value open communication. I'm comfortable working in fast-paced environments. Learning new skills is a passion of mine, and I'm always looking for opportunities to improve my knowledge and expertise. Also, I'm pretty strong in algorithms - I've even won some national olympiads in informatics

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Ruby, Go, NodeJS, Python

Frameworks Ruby on Rails, Echo, NestJS, ExpressJS, VueJS, Django, FastAPI, React

Test frameworks Jest, RSpec

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB

Cloud AWS, GCP, Azure Web HTML5, CSS3

CI Github Actions, CircleCI

Methodologies Scrum, Kanban, OOP, Domain Driven Design, SOLID, GRASP, TDD

Other Git, Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, ElasticSearch,

Twilio, Firebase, Wells Fargo API, Intacct Sage API

EXPERIENCE

Peer Street, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA)

June 2018 - February 2023

Senior Software Engineer

Remote

- \cdot Developed and launched a financial product that attracted over \$3 million in new investments within 5 months
- · Integrated banking systems, increasing customer transactions by 44
- \cdot Automated financial operations, saving the servicing department 20 hours per day on average, reducing errors by 20
- \cdot Enhanced financial data consistency and reduced data loss by implementing Event Sourcing, decreasing data correction request times by 50
- · Advocated for Domain Driven Design and Clean Code principles, improving design/development processes and platform maintenance
- · Reviewed code and mentored other engineers, ensuring high-quality standards were maintained
- · Provided rapid feedback to product managers on feature complexity and development timelines

Silicon Valley Software Group LLC (San Francisco, CA) Software Engineer

March 2016 - April 2018

Remote

- · Led a team of three frontend developers in designing and developing complex applications using React and Node
- · Introduced unit testing and integration testing, increasing application stability
- · Established automated code reviews with linters and set up CI/CD pipelines using TravisCI, CircleCI, and Github Actions
- · Reviewed code, mentored junior developers, and fostered a culture of high-quality coding standards
- · Enhanced code quality across multiple projects during and after active development phases

Appeast Inc. (Boston, MA)

Ruby on Rails Developer

October 2015 - February 2016

Minsk, Belarus

- · Developed API services using Ruby on Rails framework
- · Refactored and optimized Cost Per Action estimation algorithm for improved performance
- · Implemented user interface features in a web application built with Angular

SivinTech LLC

December 2014 - September 2015

Ruby on Rails developer

Minsk, Belarus

- · Designed and implemented a call center for SivinTech's client, utilizing Twilio as the communication platform
- · Migrated legacy Java applet to Angular, modernizing the application and improving its performance

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University Of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk

2013 - 2017

Faculty of Computer Systems and Networks

B.S. in Computer Science & Software Engineering

Belarusian State University Of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk

2017 - 2020

Faculty of Computer Systems and Networks

M.S. in Computer Science

incomplete degree

HONORS & AWARDS

Competed in RuCTF 2015 competition as part of the team from our university. Our team took 2nd place.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2013. Took 1st degree diploma.

Competed in Individual Olympaid in Informatics and Programming in 2013. Took awardee diploma.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2012. Took 2nd degree diploma.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2011.

LINKS

Github - https://github.com/yoihito

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoihito/